TARUN DHIRAJ

Software Engineer

Bellandur, Bangalore (M) +91-8239743553 www.tarundhiraj.me tarunrdhiraj@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Hardworking and passionate software engineer with 3+ years of experience in developing robust and maintainable code. Has worked on both frontend and backend parts of distinguishing features on Cisco's ESA and contributed to several backend workflows for Life Connextions.

JOB EXPERIENCES

SOFTWARE ENGINEER II CISCO SYSTEMS Aug 2017-Present

Cisco Email Security Appliance

- Developed GUI, process and entire fields management pipeline for Consolidated Event Log support. Had managed entire team during on field testing phase
- Improved efficiency of message tracking query on Cisco Security Management Appliance by 10% by implementing a verdict chart and several log events.
- Developed various cli commands, gui pages, api code and backend code for features like AMP, SDR, URL filtering, Message Tracing, Message Tracking, DLP and several bugs involving several cross functional features/teams.
- Mentored 4 on-contract employees in ramping up on the project

<u>Leveraged Knowledge</u> in python, writing unit tests, working with perforce, git, angularJS, HTML, javascript, typescript, git kraken, bit bucket, reviewboard, cdets, rally, agile methodology.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, INTERNCISCO SYSTEMS Jan 2017 - June 2017 Cisco Email Security Appliance

- Improved efficiency of SenderBase Telemetry System by 5%
- Improved AMP feature usability by building an AMP Appliance Grouping page.
- Developed few user stories as part of AMP Scrum Team.

<u>Leveraged Knowledge</u> in setting up performance testbed setup, profiling of processes using coro profiler, working in Agile teams, using rally and CDETs to track bugs, working with FreeBSD systems, aquarium framework, perforce.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER PERSISTENT SYSTEMSNov 2014 – June 2015 Life Connextions (Now, Optum)

- Worked as a backend engineer in developing business logic in visual process modeler (written entirely in Java).
- Implemented business logic to manage dependents of a life insurance buyer.

<u>Leveraged Knowledge</u> in managing code using Tortoise VPN, working with Java codebase, visual process modeler, MySQL database, optimizing JVM, working with Linux systems.

PROJECT INTERN PERSISTENT SYSTEMSAug 2013 – April 2014 ParkMeRight – A Smart Parking System

- Among top 5 selected from GHRCE
- Created fronted, rest service and database for a smart parking system <u>Leveraged Knowledge</u> in developing pages using HTML5, JS, rest service using java's jersey library, and data management using MySQL database.

PROJECTS

Personal Website (tarundhiraj.me)

• For additional information and projects

BrainF*ck Interpreter

- Developed a web-based application that takes a brainf*ck source code as an input, interprets it and displays the result.
- <u>Utilized</u>: cherrypy, python, HTML, JS.

CLI Based IaaS and SaaS application

- Developed a cli based laaS and Storage aaS application in C++.
- <u>Utilized</u>: C++, libvert, ngrest, Linux system

Smart Garbage Collection System

- Developed a smart garbage collection system for BITS campus.
- <u>Utilized</u>: Arduino Uno, ultrasonic distance sensor.

EDUCATION

Master of Engineering (ME) 2015 - 2017 BITS Pilani, Pilani Campus. CGPA: 8.20 Bachelor of Engineering (BE) 2010 - 2014 GHRCE, Nagpur CGPA: 9.89 12th AISSCE (CBSE) 2008 - 2009 KV 9BRD, Pune 84.4 % 10th AISSE (CBSE) 2006 - 2007 KV 9BRD, Pune 91.4 %

SKILLS

Proficient: Java, Python, Perforce, Git, MySQL

Familiar: C++, AngularJS, HTML5, JS, TypeScript

ACHIEVEMENTS

- AIR 1302 GATE 2015
- Among top 25 selected in BITS HD 2015
- Among top 25 selected in PGEEE, IIIT Hyderabad
- Among 5% selected for Merit Scholarship cum 40% Fee Waiver, BITS Pilani.
- Silver Medal for scoring 2nd rank in entire college and 1st rank in CS branch, GHRCE.
- Award of Academic Excellence in all years of bachelor's study, GHRCE.
- Elected and successfully lead GHRCE CS fests as General Secretary and President.
- 0.1% Merit Certificate from CBSE for scoring 100 in Sanskrit, awarded only to top 0.1% students
- Recipient of AFWWA and AF scholarships from Indian Air Force, awarded only to consistent top performers in academics.

HOBBIES

Listening to music, Playing badminton, football, Photography

LANGUAGES

English, Hindi

SOCIAL CONNECT

github.com/tarundhiraj
linkedin.com/in/tarundhiraj/